亲爱的福尔摩斯
My Dear Holmes,
今天我步行了14英里 穿越了崎岖的地势
today I walked 14 miles across rough terrain
腿脚或肩膀却没有感到 丝毫酸痛
and hardly a twinge from either my leg or my shoulder.
风景正如传说中一样美丽
The landscape is as handsome as it is reported.
我仍然希冀
I still entertain the hope
能说服你也与我同行
that I can prevail upon you to join me.
当然我理解
I appreciate, of course,
大自然的美丽对你几乎没有意义
that the beauties of nature mean little to you,
但我相信你会发现
but I believe you would have found
在我下榻旅馆里的几位客人 非常引人注意
some of the guests at my hotel most intriguing.
道德的光辉闪耀在一位
Moral splendor is on display in the person
叫Shlessinger的少校身上
of the striking Major Shlessinger,
一位布尔战争的英雄
a hero of the Boer War,
不幸在Ladysmith保卫战斗中 成了瘸子
sadly crippled in the defense of Ladysmith
现在投身于慈善事业
and now engaged in charitable work.
Calder女士是他的护士
His nurse is a Ms. Calder
值得注意的是 她不仅是他的信徒
whose attentiveness suggests not only that she is his disciple but also
而且或许里面还有更为亲密的感情
that tenderer feelings may be involved.
然而  最令人雀跃的是
Most fascinating of all, however,
一位非常杰出的女士
is an extraordinary woman,
能在任何群体中脱颖而出的人
one who would stand out in any society,
Frances Carfax女士
the Lady Frances Carfax.
我想有人会觉得她很前卫
I suppose one would call her modern
除了她似乎是来自
except that she seems to come from
某个古老的英国怪异贵族的分支
an ancient line of English eccentrics.
昨天 像是要证明自己的特立独行
Yesterday, as if to confirm the general opinion of her oddity,
她声称她会
she declared that she would
自己驾船穿过湖泊去教堂
sail herself to church across the lake.
在旅馆的马车上 大家还纷纷猜测着
There was much speculation in the hotel carriage
在前往湖边那座 精致的小礼拜堂的路上
as we traveled towards the charming little lakeside chapel
谈论Frances女士是否
about whether Lady Frances
能像她所说的那么能干
would be as good as her word.
而其中居然愚蠢到怀疑她的人
And those of us foolish enough to doubt her
很快就因出现在浅滩上的小船 而自食其言
were soon rebuked by the sight of a skiff moored in the shallows
还有因为那位像我们招呼时 目光灼灼的船长
and by the stern gaze of its captain when she greeted us within.
一次出人意料的精彩布道 牧师
A surprisingly jolly sermon, Vicar,
非常之惊喜
a lot like a cat.
她不仅不在乎给大家留下的印象
Well, she appears to care not a jot what her fellow guests make of her
似乎也对自己给所到之处
and seems quite insensible to the vivid impression
留下的活泼身影毫无察觉
she creates wherever she goes.
我们都被逗乐了
We were all amused certainly
看着她努力把小船驶离岸边
at the sight of her trying to board the skiff,
但既然她有本事开船而来
but since she had accomplished the outward journey with such skill,
我们没有理由认为
we had no reason to suppose
她的返程会碰上更大的困难
that her return voyage would present her with any greater difficulty
或者会预料到最后的结果
or that it would end in the way that it did.
我决定翻越小山走回去
I had decided to walk back across the fill
这样我就不必留在那些等待
so I was not amongst those who waited
为Frances女士返航庆祝的人群中
to cheer Lady Frances on her return.
我比预计的时间晚到了一点
I arrived a little later at exactly the moment
当时的情况真是千钧一发
when tragedy threatened to strike.
救命!
Help!
救命 在这里!
Help, here!
救命!
Help!
我当时无能为力 亲爱的福尔摩斯
I was helpless, my dear Holmes,
无能为力
helpless.
在我的一生中 我从未如此 感到自己的无力
I have never felt so powerless in my life,
我本以为有人与我一样
as powerless so I thought
那位坐在自己轮椅上的老兵
as the old soldier in his wheelchair
也只能拼命呼救 来寻求帮助
who had only been able to shout, it seemed, for help.
凭着阅历
As with many men,
我早就注意到 一个某部分有残疾的人
I have noticed a weakness in one part of the body
作为补偿 其它地方会有惊人的力量
is compensated by great strength elsewhere.
尽管无法行走
Unable to walk,
Shlessinger仍然能够奋力在水中游泳
Shlessinger was yet able to swim powerfully
仅仅靠他的臂膀
with his arms alone.
后来旅馆的援兵也及时赶到了
Reinforcements arrived in due course from the hotel,
一场悲剧就这样被避免了
and tragedy was happily averted.
现在 一切恢复正常
Now, all parties are recovered,
据说Frances女士
it is reported that the Lady Frances
不满自己的获救
is resentful of her rescue
就好像是她的女权主张
as if her suffragette principles
因此会成了一种让步
had been somehow compromised.
但所有人都认同
All agree at any rate
Shlessinger少校是当时的英雄
that Major Shlessinger is the hero of the hour.
现在Calder女士的精力 都放到了霸道的爱慕上
Ms. Calder's attentions are now translated into patent adoration.
毫无疑问 在明天旅馆里
No doubt further praise will be in order
在他进行的传教士活动上
when he lectures on his missionary activities
一定会听到更多的赞美之词
at the hotel tomorrow.
顺便说一句 他是 基督医疗福音教会的英国代表
He is, by the way, the British representative of the Mission Church of Christ the Healer
基地就在秘鲁的安第斯高地
whose theater works in the high Andes of Peru.
早上好
Morning.
Shlessinger少校在回避我
Major Shlessinger is avoiding me.
可怜的人在为自己的 英勇行为感到尴尬
The poor man is embarrassed by his own heroism.
也许他现在认为 我有义务为他的事业出一份力
Perhaps he now thinks I'm obliged to contribute to his work.
人就是有这样显著的弱点
Men have such extraordinary weaknesses.
你不这么想吗?
Don't you think.
哦 是的 当然了 我们就是这样 当然 我赞同
Oh, yes, certainly, we do, of course, I agree.
你介意到湖边转一转吗 医生
Would you care to take a turn by the lake, Doctor?
Shlessinger少校为他的教会 不知疲倦的工作
Major Shlessinger works tirelessly for his church,
不是吗
does he not?
我明白他们需要大笔的资金
I understand the need for funds is considerable.
明天他会在旅馆举办讲座
He's lecturing on his cause tomorrow
希望能筹集到一些资金
here in the hotel hoping to raise some money.
他会大有收获
He'll do well.
当地妇女会很乐意各自 捐出半个几尼(英国旧金币)
The local matronage will happily part with half a guinea each
得到一个和这样一位男士 在公共场所相处的机会
for the company of such a man all be it in public.
我吓到你了吗
Do I shock you?
一点也没有
Not at all.
我吓到了我的哥哥
I shock my brother.
作为Rufton伯爵
As the Earl of Rufton,
我想他觉得有义务被吓到
I think he feels it is his duty to be shocked.
啊 这里很漂亮 不是吗
Oh, it's very beautiful here, isn't it?
我童年的每个夏天 都在这湖边度过
I spent every summer of my childhood here by this lake.
美轮美奂
It's very beautiful.
确实如此
It is indeed.
他明天会来看望我
He's to visit me tomorrow.
谁?
Who?
我的哥哥
My brother.
这也是义务 当然了
That is duty, too, of course.
该死的他
Damn him.
该死的他!
啊  Frances女士
Ah, Lady Frances.
真是令人惊喜
What a pleasant surprise.
我必须承认她的行为
I must confess that her behavior
始终让我着迷
continues to fascinate me.
我承认她对这个陌生的
I grant that her reaction to this
骑马者的反应非常激烈
unknown horseman was extreme,
但她的许多反应都是这样
but many of her reactions are.
她是不是认识他呢 我在猜想
Had she known him, I wonder?
过去发生了什么 让她对他如此害怕
What lies in her past to prompt this fear of him?
为了寻找答案
In looking for an explanation,
我期待着
I am placing some hopes
今天下午 Rufton伯爵
in the visit we expect this afternoon
她哥哥的到访
from her brother, the Earl of Rufton.
据说 他的古怪与他妹妹
By all accounts,his oddities are of an entirely different order
正好相反
from those of his sister.
当她在嘲笑传统时
Where she flouts convention,
他会把过去时代的习俗
he has raised the conventions of a former era
上升到信仰的高度
to the status of a faith.
而说到自己
As for myself,
我注意到自己越来越漠视
I notice an increasing indifference
周围的秀色美景
to the natural beauty which lies about me.
我的思绪时常回到
My thoughts return constantly
Frances女士
to the Lady Frances.
她的一些事情
There is something about her life
会激起我的同情心
which prompts my sympathy,
一些我可以感受到的悲伤
some unhappiness I can sense
令我想把它们驱散
which I would dearly like to dispel.
我寄希望她的精神
It is to be hoped that her spirits
能随着她哥哥的来访而恢复
will be lifted by her brother's visit
不要再压抑
for she remains subdued
昨天与那陌生人的偶遇而产生的心情
from yesterday's strange encounter.
他是谁  福尔摩斯
Who is he, Holmes?
为什么他不希望自己被认出
Why does he not wish to make himself known?
到底是为什么
Why indeed?
华生  你真有份好心肠
Watson, you're a brick.
我来到这里  Fanny 是想知道你的近况
I came here, Fanny, to see how you were,
而不是被说教
not to be lectured.
这不是说教而是请求
It's not a lecture, it's a request.
这听起来就像是说教
It sounds like a lecture.
其实很简单 我需要些钱
It's quite simple, I need some money.
就这样吗?
Just like that?
我想你又做得过分了  是不是
I suppose you've been overdoing again, haven't you?
我没有过分  John
I do not overdo it, John.
如果我花了太多
If I have ever overspent
你给我的那丁点零花钱
the wretched allowance you've given me,
那是因为有人需要帮助
it's because someone has been in need.
哦 是啊 你那著名的金子般的心
Oh, yes, your famous heart of gold,
除了那都是我的钱 现在也没了
except that it's my money, and there isn't any.
你是非常清楚的 没有了
You know perfectly well there isn't.
我们已经大不如前
The hall is falling to bits.
在东翼有了猫头鹰的家族
There's a family of owls in the east wing,
你自己想想吧
and you think.
现在又是什么呢
What is it this time?
帮助在Islington身无分文的诗人
Helping penniless poets in Islington?
你只知道如何地残酷 是吧
You only know how to be cruel, don't you?
你什么时候在乎过我要什么
When have you ever cared for what I want?
我过去15年的岁月是如此可怜
The last 15 years of my life have been wretched
而现在 至少 我有机会
and now, at last, I had a chance
能做点什么事
to make something of it.
这难道对你没有任何意义吗
Doesn't that have any meaning for you?
下午好
Good Afternoon.
我看不出任何区别
I don't see what difference it makes.
区别就在于
The difference it makes
我一直都在被你指挥
is that I'm being told what to do.
你知道我讨厌这样
You know I loathe it.
问题是你从来就不听取意见
The trouble is you won't even take advice,
不是吗
will you?
一切都给了你
You've been offered everything.
却统统被你拒绝了
You've turned it all down.
给了我什么?
What have I been offered?
婚姻  美满的婚姻
Marriage, good marriages.
哈 哈 哈...
Ha, ha, ha.
给一个有头衔的乡下人做免费的奴隶
To be the unpaid slave of a titled yokel
这种人连书都没看过一本
who hasn't even read a book,
以为巴赫(音乐家)是种小猎犬
who thinks Bach is something terriers do.
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
你还有什么反对我的理由?
What have you got against me doing this?
有什么?
What?
我要远离这种可悲混乱的生活
I want to get out of this miserable mess my life is in
看在上帝的份上 让我做自己
to be my own woman, for God's sake,
让我过一段充实的日子
to fulfill just a portion of my life.
你为什么总是拖我的后腿
Why do you always hold me back?
好好想想  John
Think of it, John,
好好想想
think of it.
只要一笔钱
Just one payment.
就一次
One.
你就可以永远摆脱我了
You could see the back of me forever.
正如我们展示的骡子运输
The mule express as we have dubbed it
每个月会递送邮件
brings the mail once a month.
信件 当然了
Letters, of course,
来自基督图书馆的精神粮食
and food for the mind from the Library of Christ.
以及为我的人们带来健康的药品
And medicines for the well being of my flock
就是这群你们看到的站在楼外 临时钟楼下的人们
whom you may see here posing outside the mission below a temporary belfry.
在我向你们展示下一幅
When I show you the next picture
我教会中一名领导成员的照片时
of a leading member of my congregation,
你就会明白牧羊人和迷失的羔羊的寓言
you will understand how the parable of the shepherd and the lost sheep
为什么在我们的传教中改成了
has become transmuted in our teaching
牧人和迷失的美洲驼
into that of the llama herd and the lost llama.
最后是我们的教堂
And finally, our church,
虽然简陋 粗糙 破烂
humble as it is, rough and poor indeed,
我可以骄傲地说
I'm proud to tell you
上帝的言语
that the word of God
在其中被激情地宣讲
is preached as fervently within its walls
并收到了热烈欢快的响应
and is as joyously received there
正如在本土的大教堂里一样
as in any great cathedral here at home.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
正如我预料中的鼓舞人心
It was inspiring as I predicted.
我很遗憾地说Shlessinger少校 行程紧凑 马不停蹄
I regret to say that the rigors of his itinerary press hard upon Major Shlessinger
很快就要出发去Whitehaven
who will shortly be departing for Whitehaven.
就让我们为了他可敬的传教团开始募捐吧
We shall be taking up a collection on behalf of his estimable mission, of course.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说你能自己补救
I mean that the remedy lies in your own hands.
怎么做?
How?
你知道该怎么做
You know how.
如果你是认真的 你会知道怎么做
If you're really serious, you'll know what to do,
该死
damn it.
我厌恶了你总是来求助于我
I'm sick of you coming to me
就为了这些疯狂的念头
with these crackpot notions.
你知道我的责任
You know my responsibilities.
如果你没有放弃所有给你的机会
If you hadn't thrown away all your chances,
也不会落到现在这个田地
you wouldn't be in this position now.
我已经受够了
Well, I've had enough.
你知道你该做什么
You know what you have to do.
成熟点 去做吧
Grow up and do it.
我最后的求助 这真的是我最后的求助
My last resort, my very last resort.
你怎么能这么说
How can you suggest it.
马夫
Groom.
你到底在哪里
Where the devil are you?
Shlessinger先生的见面会 是在哪个房间举行
In which room is Mr. Shlessinger's meeting taking place?
我恐怕见面会已经在 半小时前结束了 女士
I am afraid the meeting finished half an hour ago, madam.
Shlessinger先生即刻就要 动身去Whitehaven
Mr. Shlessinger will have left for Whitehaven by now.
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
是的 我忘记了
Yes, I've forgotten.
谢谢
Thank you.
Frances女士
Lady Frances.
别来纠缠我!
Leave me alone.
抱歉
Excuse me.
你 先生
You, sir.
无容置疑
I've no doubt
你会告诉我这是无谓的担心 福尔摩斯
you will tell me my fears are unfounded, Holmes,
但那个人的反复出现
but the repeated appearance of this man
已经为她的生活蒙上了阴影
has cast a shadow over her life
无论她多努力还是无法摆脱
which try as she might she cannot lift.
"...Elmyria号上的悲剧 Rosenbloom家族继承人溺水身亡"
*PAPER*
晚报 福尔摩斯先生
Evening paper, Mr. Holmes?
Hudson太太 给我找辆出租车
Mrs. Hudson, fetch me a cab.
Hudson太太
Mrs. Hudson.
等电报局一开门
As soon as the telegraph office is opened,
就给John 华生医生去份电报
to Dr. John Watson,
湖滨旅馆  Felmire  Cumberland
Lake Hotel, Felmire, Cumberland.
内容是什么  福尔摩斯先生
And what of Mr. Holmes?
我就要走了 Hudson太太
I shall not be here, Mrs. Hudson.
华生医生
Dr. Watson.
我会在8:17离开Uston的车上
I shall be on the 8:17 out of Uston.
华生医生
Dr. Watson.
我的车在楼下等你
My cab awaits you downstairs.
快读
Read.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
快读
Read.
巨大的危险 Frances女士 句号
Grave danger Lady Frances, stop.
不要让她走出视线 句号
Never let from sight, stop.
我在路上 福尔摩斯
On my way, Holmes.
这份电报来了多久?
How long has this been here?
我 嗯
I um.
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
失踪了 华生
Disappeared, Watson.
失踪了
Disappeared.
Frances女士结账了吗
Did Lady Frances pay her bill?
没有先生
No, sir.
她有叫任何交通工具吗
Did she order any transport?
不 先生
No, sir.
她有拿走自己的行李吗
And she took none of her luggage?
我想没有 先生
We think not, sir.
福尔摩斯先生在哪里
Where is Mr. Holmes?
没有任何消息 福尔摩斯
Nothing yet, Holmes.
我开始害怕最坏的结果
I'm beginning to fear the worst.
要怪我自己
I blame myself.
我知道我该抓住那个人
I knew I should have pursued that fellow.
有一个可能性
It is a possibility.
是什么
What is?
你还没看出来吗 再明显不过了
Do you not see it? It is most conspicuous.
什么
What?
小船 华生 驶走的小船
The skiff, Watson, the sailing skiff.
不在这里了
It's not here.
非常正确
Precisely.
很可能Frances Carfax女士在上面
It is possible there lies the Lady Frances Carfax
悄悄地去了Avonside
silent road to Avonside.
这是众所周知的最近的终点
It is the nearest railhead as you know.
你是说这个人用船绑架走了她?
You don't mean that this fellow abducted her by boat?
丝绸
Silk.
这是三个最大可能性之一
It is one of the three more likely possibilities.
最佳的法国缝纫  鸽灰色
Best French sewn, dove gray.
她有一条灰色丝绸的披肩
She had a gray silk shawl.
不 没有更有价值的线索了
No, well, that will tell us nothing more.
是哪三个可能性  福尔摩斯
What are the three possibilities, Holmes?
她通常在什么衣服时会戴上披肩?
In what did she usually wear the shawl?
她外出时的衣服
Oh, her outside clothes.
哪三个可能性?!
The three possibilities?
她可能和预谋的绑匪一起走了
She may have run away with her intended abductor.
或如你所说她被人用船绑架走了
He may have abducted her by boat as you suggest
或是其他方法
or by some other means.
也许她...考虑到她目前的情绪
She may, considering her emotional condition,
被人乘虚而入受骗出走
have been deceived into going with him.
这太难让人相信了
I can hardly believe that.
她非常害怕他 相信我
She was terrified of him, believe me.
我相信你
I believe you.
是的
Yes.
在狐狸的世界里迷路的小鸡
A stray chicken in the world of foxes.
一旦她被抓了 就不会失踪了
Once she's gobbled up, she's hardly missed.
来吧  华生
Come, Watson.
我们的马应该备好了
And our horses should be saddled by now.
马?
Horses?
我选择骑马也许有些过分了
I have been somewhat extravagant in choice of mounts,
但拖延会在这时产生危险
but delay must be dangerous in this matter.
我们要在黄昏时到达Rufton伯爵府
We should be at Rufton Hall at dusk.
我不知道什么让你这么有兴趣 先生
I don't see what possible interest it could have for you, sir.
我向你保证 非常吸引我
Considerable interest I assure you.
世界上最危险的事情之一
One of the most dangerous classes in the world
就是单身的漂泊女子
is the drifting and friendless woman
得不到保护和指引
with no one to protect and guide her.
不可避免地会诱使别人犯罪
She is the inevitable inciter of crime in others.
我对你妹妹失踪这件事
I treat the disappearance of your sister
抱着非常严肃的态度
with utmost seriousness.
你以为我不是吗
Do you think I do not?
我不过是说你有点计较了
I'm merely suggesting that it is frivolous
不肯告诉我你们到底在争吵什么
to keep from me the substance of your quarrel.
就是在争吵之后
It was after all this quarrel
她紧接着就失踪了
which immediately preceded her disappearance.
也许这和她曾经认识的
Might it have something to do
酗酒的诗人有关呢?
with a drunken poet she once knew?
什么?
What?
我从同事那获悉
I understand of my colleague
她或许最近见过他
that she may have seen him recently.
Green吗?
Green?
我以为那是最后一次见他
I thought I'd seen the last of him.
我15年前就打发他走了
I sent him packing, 15 years ago.
他和你妹妹是什么关系
What is his connection with your sister?
他曾追求过她
He used to court her.
一个活生生的畜牲
Great brute of a fellow.
她本不该和他扯上半点关系
She wouldn't have anything to do with him.
尊贵的Philip Green
The Honorable Philip Green.
没有比它更被玷污的名字了
Never was a title so abused.
他完全堕落了
He went to the dogs completely,
酗酒 赌博
drink, gambling.
最终在Islington破产
Ended up destitute in Islington
假装在写诗
pretending to write poetry.
当然  就在他一无所有的时候 Frances开始对他着迷
Of course, Frances became interested in him as soon as he lost everything.
你是怎么打发他的
How did you send him packing?
他是个野蛮的人
He was a violent fellow,
还酗酒
and he drank.
我听说有人要告他
I'd heard talk of prosecution,
欠债  人身伤害
debt, assault.
我给了他100镑
I gave him 100 pounds
买了张去澳大利亚的票给他
and bought him a ticket to Australia.
要是他再在这里出现
Show his face around here,
我会放狗咬他
I'll set the dogs on him.
说说你和你妹妹的争吵
Now, your quarrel with your sister.
钱
Money.
她想要钱
She wanted money.
她自己没有钱吗
She has none of her own?
我从财产中拨出一份零用钱给她
I make her an allowance out of the estate.
不多也不少 你看到这里了
It's modest, but you've seen the place.
她自己没有财产吗
She has no assets herself?
不 她有的
Yes, she has.
我告诉过她如果她需要钱
I told her if she wanted money,
她可以把这个卖了
she could sell this.
这是无价的藏品
It's a priceless collection.
这是Fragenalt为法国皇家设计的
That was designed for the French royal family by Fragenalt.
我们在大革命时得到的
We acquired it all at the revolution,
而现在 都是她的了
and now, it's hers.
我有的就是猫头鹰
What I have is owls,
在东翼的猫头鹰
owls in the east wing.
想看看猫头鹰吗
Want to see the owls?
她把这些放在哪里
Where does she keep them?
她旅行时会带在身边吗
Does she travel with them?
不
No.
那么现在它们被放在哪里
Well, now, where are they kept?
我的天啊 你的妹妹消失了
My Lord, your sister has vanished.
如何和为什么我们都还不知道
How and why we do not know,
但我有理由相信
but I have reason to believe
她的处境非常危险
she is in the gravest danger.
我们知道了珠宝所在
Were we to know the where abouts of the jewelry,
也许就有救她的机会
we might have some chance of saving her.
在Pall Mall的Oxford&Lombard海事银行
The Oxford and Lombard Maritime Bank in Pall Mall.
谢谢
Thank you.
Oxford&Lombard银行
The Oxford and Lombard Bank
12小时后才开门
opens its doors in 12 hours.
她可能已经来了又走了
She may already have come and gone.
银行已经开门20分钟了
The bank's been open for 20 minutes.
我真是有眼无珠 福尔摩斯
I've been quite blind, Holmes.
证据就在我的掌握之中
I had the evidence in the palm of my hand.
要是她有什么意外  我会...
If anything's happened to her, I shall...
福尔摩斯  快看
Holmes, look.
我能帮忙吗 先生
May I help you, sir?
是的  我想见见经理
Yes, please, I wish to see the manager.
一项业务
It's a part of a deal.
关系到一个家族在贵行寄存的私人物品
It's a private matter concerning a family deposit with the bank.
我的同事...
My colleague.
华生!
Watson.
你 先生!
You, sir?
我吗 先生?
I, sir?
就是你
You, sir.
你对Frances Carfax女士做了什么
What have you done with the Lady Frances Carfax?
我坚持要个答案
I insist upon an answer.
Frances!
怪我自己
I blame myself.
不 你不必
No, you need not.
无论如何 我还是会
Nevertheless, I do.
我们都该自责
We all bear equal blame.
她又失踪了 就是这样
She's disappeared again, and that is that.
再强调也没有意义了
It is pointless to dwell on it.
我们现在的任务是找到她
Our task now is to find her.
Green先生
Mr. Green,
让我们回到那一刻
let us go back to that moment
昨天早上在湖边
by the lake yesterday morning.
我在黎明骑马外出
I was out riding in the dawn,
我看到了小船
and I saw the skiff
朝着Ironside 穿湖而去
sailing across the lake toward Ironside.
而你知道那是Frances女士
And you realized that it was the Lady Frances?
是的
Yes.
她是一个人吗
Was she alone?
是的
Yes.
请继续
Please continue.
我设法乘上了同一辆火车
I managed to board the same train.
我求她和我说话
I begged her to speak to me.
我告诉她我周游了世界
I told her how I'd traveled the world
成了一个非常富有的人
and had become a very rich man.
我告诉她我从未停止爱她
I told her that I'd never stopped loving her
她可以得到任何她想要的东西
and that she could have whatever she wanted.
我现在可以见她了
I can see her now.
她坐在那里什么也没有说
She sat saying nothing,
像斯芬克斯那样微笑 (埃及的狮身人面)
smiling like a sphinx.
不 她说道
No, she said.
她想要过自己的生活
She wanted to go her own way.
当我们来到伦敦
When we got to London,
我努力尾随着她
I followed her as best I could,
但她似乎下定决心要甩掉我
but she seemed determined to be rid of me.
我在靠近Sellick桥的地方跟丢了她
I lost her somewhere near Sellick Bridge.
Sellick?
最有趣的部分
Oh, that is most interesting.
为什么
Why?
有可靠消息 他常去的地方
I'm reliably informed that his usual haunts
是威斯敏斯特的的西部
are west of Westminster.
谁常去的地方
Who's haunts?
你怎么会出现在银行的?
How did you come to be at the bank?
我猜她在伦敦需要钱
I reasoned that she would be needing money while she was in London,
我也知道他们家族所托银行的地址
and I know the address of the family bank well enough.
我有个疯狂的想法
I had the wild idea
想向那的经理寻求帮助
of enlisting the manager's help.
你知道她在哪吗  福尔摩斯先生
Do you know where she is, Mr. Holmes?
不 我不知道
No, I do not.
那你觉得她会在哪里
Where do you think she is?
我相信通过我们的努力能够救出她
I believe that through our efforts to save her,
我们已经把她推向了她最坏的敌人
we have driven her into the hands of her worst enemy.
但我们看到她是自由的
But we saw her free.
我亲爱的华生
My dear Watson,
一个人会在悬崖边行走
a person may walk over the edge of the cliff
是因为他们被邀请去赏月
because they've been invited to gaze at the moon.
她的眼睛或许睁着
Her eyes may be open,
但是...我相信在这一刻
but she is I believe at this moment
她正踏入致命的危险
walking into mortal danger.
Shlessinger
Shlessinger.
Shlessinger先生
Mr. Shlessinger.
过去的一周里我去充分解了 世界各地罗马教廷的传教团
This last week I sought to acquaint myself with the world of apostolic missions.
我还查询了苏格兰场的档案
I've also made a search of the records of Scotland Yard.
Shlessinger
Shlessinger,
也就是Joseph Cubbington牧师
is also known as the Reverend Joseph Cubbington,
Amos Callow Masaro的地区主教
Amos Callow, the Dean of Masaro
也是Edmund 利马(秘鲁首都)的主教
and Edmund, the Bishop of Lima.
事实上 他的真名是Peters
His real name, in fact, is Peters.
一个厚颜无耻的骗子
He's a confidence trickster
在苏格兰场被没有新意地被称为"圣彼得"
known at Scotland Yard by the uninspired logic of that place as Holy Peters.
虽然至今没有疑点
What is not yet suspected
但毫无疑问
but incontrovertible nonetheless
他是个刽子手
is that he is a murderer.
Peters的专长是
Peters specialty,
利用宗教信仰和善良的心地 诓骗单身女子
is the beguiling of single woman with private means by playing on their religious and charitable feelings.
Helena Rosenbloom 为慈善事业献身十载
Helena Rosenbloom had been engaged in charitable work for ten years
当她遇到Shlessinger后
when she met Shlessinger.
她被鼓励投身于在安格斯的新传教团上
He inspired her to devote her energies to a new mission in the Andes.
于是Rosenbloom女士 改变了她的遗嘱
Ms. Rosenbloom changed her will,
告别了她之前的生活
said good-bye to her former life
在Glasgow登上了SS Elmyria号
and boarded the SS Elmyria at Glasgow
准备前往南美
bound for South America.
她在海上失踪了
She was lost overboard
就在出海的第一个晚上
the first night at sea.
于是SS Elmyria号在利物浦做了停靠
The SS Elmyria docked at Liverpool
以便她的家人取回她的遗物
for the family to retrieve her effects.
Shlessinger也上了岸
Shlessinger also disembarked.
他在Lake District落脚
He went to ground at the Lake District
结识了他的下一个受害者
where he met his next intended victim,
Frances Carfax女士
the Lady Frances Carfax.
终于 先生们
At last, gentlemen,
终于
at last.
它在哪里被典当的?
Where was it pawned?
Stockwall的Riley当铺
Riley's of Stockwall.
我数了下 正好是我前往的第27间
It was by my calculation the 27th shop I tried.
据我所知 Riley因为收赃 而受到过两次法庭的宣判
Riley has received two sentences to my knowledge for the receipt of stolen goods.
他会和我们合作的
He will cooperate with us.
这是什么意思
What does this mean?
什么意思!
What does it mean?
别这样 Green先生 这没有用
Please, Mr. Green, this is pointless.
别折磨你自己
Don't torture yourself.
你觉得我愿意折磨自己吗?
Do you think the torture is self-induced?
想到Frances落在罪犯手里
The thought of Frances in the hands of criminals.
我没法不去想 福尔摩斯先生
Such thoughts come unbidden, Mr. Holmes.
它们穿透了我的大脑 能筑起的最强的防线
They break through the strongest defenses the mind can  raise against them.
冷静 Green先生
Calm yourself, Mr. Green,
冷静
calm yourself.
如果她还对Shlessinger 的真实身份一无所知
If she's still innocent of Shlessinger's true identify,
也许现在还是安全的
she may well be safe for a time.
要是不是呢?
And if not?
那么显然他不会就这么 轻易地放过她
Then it is clear that he cannot let her loose without his own destruction.
现在 我们必须继续希望
Now, we must continue to hope
她仍然不知道他是谁
that she remains ignorant of who he is.
十五年
Fifteen years.
我知道自己在没有所成前 是没脸回来的
I knew I could never come back  until I'd made something of myself.
也许我这么想很愚蠢
Perhaps it was foolish of me to think
希望她会在这些年后
that she would look kindly on me
她会好好对我
after all these years,
但我可笑地因为她一直没结婚
but I was ridiculously encouraged by the fact
这样的事实所鼓舞
that she was not married.
而现在 我的愚蠢把她
And now, my stupidity has driven her
推向了凶手的怀抱
into the arms of a murderer.
我能做什么
What can I do?
我什么都不能做吗?
Is there nothing I can do?
Shlessinger看见过你吗
Does Shlessinger know you by sight?
没有
No.
啊  那么有件事你能做
Ah, well, then there is something that you can do.
但这需要你的耐心
But it'll demand great patience.
我已经等了15年了 福尔摩斯先生
I have waited for 15 years, Mr. Holmes.
Shlessinger希望珠宝能卖个好价钱
Shlessinger's had a fair price for the jewelry
而且不要被追问
and no questions asked.
他肯定会再到Riley的店里
He'll almost certainly return to Riley's shop.
还有Rosenbloom的遗物
And Rosenblooms attorney for the will.
现在 把这张纸条给Riley
Now, give this note to Riley.
他会让你在店里等候
He will let you wait at the shop.
可能会等很长时间
It may be a long wait,
但你必须要保持耐心
but you possess your soul in patience.
最重要的是 不要使用暴力
And above all, no violence.
延误了
It's late.
应该早就到了
Well, it should have been here before now.
他们说过这比普通的更花时间
Well, they say it took longer being out of the ordinary.
亲爱的 提醒我一下地址
The address, dear, remind me.
是的 先生 我能帮忙吗
Yes, sir, can I help?
Argyle大街
Argyle Street.
我在找Argyle大街
I'm looking for Argyle Street.
在路口有个邮局
There's a post office round the corner.
问问那里吧
Try there.
Green先生 没有逮捕令 我们什么也不能做
Mr. Green, we can do nothing without a warrant.
我忍不下去了
This is intolerable.
在我们有了那个可怜的纸上签名之前
Until we have some wretched signature
我们什么也不能做
on a piece of paper, we can do nothing.
同时 这些恶棍可以随意摆布她
Meanwhile, these fiends can do with her what they will.
你确定 你告诉了我所有的细节?
Are you certain that you've told me every detail?
所有的细节 我发誓
Every detail, I promise.
那把这字条送到苏格兰场
Then take this note to Scotland Yard.
他们会明白其中的紧迫
They will understand the urgency of it.
那我在那里等逮捕令
And I am to wait there for the warrant.
你今天是不可能拿到的
You will not get it today.
什么?
What?
有些延迟是不可避免的
Some delay is inevitable.
必须先找到当地法官
A magistrate must be found.
法律程序我们只能推动它 不能驱赶它
The process of the law can be  encouraged but not goaded.
看在上帝的份上 明天就太晚了
Tomorrow may be too late for God's sake.
Green先生
Mr. Green,
能做的一切我们都会做
everything that can be done will be done.
去吧
Go.
-明天就真的太晚了 -我很清楚
-Tomorrow may indeed be too late. -I'm well aware of it.
带上武器  华生
Arm yourself, Watson.
我们得一如既往地 不按常理出牌
We are as usual the irregulars
必须去碰碰运气
who must take our luck together
正如我们过去偶尔所为
as we have occasionally done in the past.
明天早上八点
8:00 tomorrow morning,
Brickston公墓
Brickston Cemetery.
我想你被指错了路 先生
I fancy that you've been misdirected, sir.
也许你该上街走到底试试
Possibly if you try further down the street.
会的
That will do.
我们没时间浪费了
We have no time to waste.
你是Harry Peters
You are Harry Peters,
之后是Albert Shlessinger少校
late Major Albert Shlessinger,
布尔战争的老兵
veteran of the Boer War.
更多的化名
Your further aliases
我就不重复了 免得让你无聊
I will not bore you by repeating.
你的名字是什么
And what is your name?
夏洛克 福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
我的朋友和同伴 我想你认识
My friend and companion I think you know.
这所房子很快就会在警方的监视下
The house will shortly be under police observation
直到逮捕令到达
until a warrant is prepared
得到搜索的授权
authorizing a search of the premises.
你的名字没有吓到我  福尔摩斯先生
Your name does not frighten me, Mr. Holmes.
我没有什么可隐瞒的
I have nothing to hide.
你有何贵干
What is your business?
我在找Frances Carfax女士
I'm looking for the Lady Frances Carfax.
很高兴听你这么说
I'm delighted to hear it.
如果有人能找到她  我想那就是你
If anyone can find her, I imagine you can.
也许到时候你能好心地来通知我一声
Perhaps you'd be so good as to tell me when you do.
我有一张她将近100英镑的欠条
I've a note against her for nearly 100 pounds,
但是还没有看到一个子儿
and nothing to show for it
除了两件假首饰
but a couple of trumpery pendants
买家连看都不想看
that the dealer would hardly look at.
这女人在骗财
The woman's a leech.
你怎么敢这么说 先生
How dare you, sir.
你在我们面前装成了 一个在战场上受伤的瘸子
You imposed upon us as a man crippled in a military action.
你才是骗子
You are a fraud.
哦 或许在你对屠杀的定义下
Oh, it may not have been a military action
那并不算是场军事行动 医生
to satisfy your standards of slaughter, Doctor,
但对我而言已经是了
but it was enough for me.
我佩服你的即兴创作
I salute your powers of improvisation, sir,
和厚颜无耻 但这没有用
and your effrontery, but it will not do.
哦 我没有在开玩笑
Oh, I'm perfectly serious.
你找到她 我就欠你们一次
You find her, and I'm your debtor.
我一定要搜查这里
I mean to go through this house until I do.
你有搜查令吗
You have a warrant?
在那之前这更有用
This will serve until a better one comes.
你这岂不是入室抢劫
Why you're a common burglar.
我的朋友是个危险的暴徒
And my friend is a dangerous ruffian.
我们就是要搜你的房子
Together we mean to go through your house.
我没有办法阻止你们
I'm in no position to stop you.
想搜查就搜吧
Search where you will.
我没什么可隐瞒的
I have nothing to hide.
你买的棺材放在哪间屋里了?
Where is the coffin that you had brought into this house?
这和你无关
That is none of your business.
我再说一次 在哪里
I repeat where?
你自说自话冲进我家
Is it not enough
用枪威胁我
that you force your way into my home,
难道还不够吗
that you threaten me at gunpoint,
你还要去打扰死者的安宁吗
must you also now invade the peace of the dead?
在哪里
Where?
我不会告诉你
I shall not tell you.
看住他 华生
Hold him here, Watson.
我不相信你会对 一个手无寸铁的人动手 医生
I don't believe you'd use that on an unarmed man, Doctor,
像我这样的情况
and in my condition.
我在印度的时候是士兵  先生
I was a soldier in India, sir.
我射杀过比你更圣洁的生物
I've shot nobler creatures than you.
灯 华生 灯
Lights, Watson, lights.
我闻到甲醛和收敛剂(凝血作用)了
I smelled formaldehyde and astringent.
感谢上帝
Thank God.
不是她
It's not her.
赶他们出去
Get them out.
你们已经打扰了死者的安息
You have violated the peace of the dead.
你们现在该离开了
You will now leave.
她是谁
Who is she?
赶他们出去
Get them out.
她的名字是Rose Spender
Her name is Rose Spender.
赶他们出去
Get them out.
她是我妻子的老护士
She is my wife's old nurse.
经在这个家已经有半个世纪了
She's been with the family for half a century.
两天前去世了
She died two days ago.
我们明天早上要埋葬她
We are to bury her tomorrow morning.
现在滚出去
Now, get out before I ask the police
趁我还没有叫来警察
you have summoned to my home
统统把你们赶出去
to come in and throw you out.
我在想这个问题 福尔摩斯
I've been considering the problem, Holmes.
在我看来
It does seem to me that they
他们还没有谋杀Frances女士
could not have murdered Lady Frances
并把她的尸体藏进棺材里
and thought to have disposed of her body in that coffin
他们只是要埋葬一个老妇人
for they would then be faced with burying the old lady.
或许这个葬礼和
It may be that this burial has no connection
Frances女士的失踪没有关系
with Lady Frances' disappearance after all.
我说过 正如你所知 她是...
I mean she was, as you know, the most
...最难被人猜测行动的人
unpredictable creature.
也许她对Shlessinger的事又考虑过
It may be that she had second thoughts about Shlessinger.
她也许察觉到了此人
She may even have had some inkling
是我们所想之人
of the kind of man we believe him to be
离开了那里
and removed herself from the house.
毕竟 他很乐意让我们搜查
He was, after all, happy to let us search it.
你怎么想?
What do you think?
你的推理是什么
What is your theory then?
我不知道
I have none.
没有足够的事实来进行推理
There are insufficient facts to construct a theory.
你觉得有东西被你忽略了吗
You think there's something you've overlooked?
延误了
It's late.
早该到了
Well, it should have been there before now.
他们说比起普通的要花更多时间
They say it took longer being out of the ordinary.
上帝赐予我的大脑究竟怎么了
What has happened to any brains that God has given me.
华生
Watson.
快点 伙计
Quick, man.
现在是生死攸关 九死一生
It's life or death. A hundred chances on death and one on life.
哦 万能的上帝 圣主啊
Oh, God most mighty, holy,
最仁慈的救世主
most merciful savior,
我们最可敬的不朽审判者
and our most worthy judge eternal,
请让我们在最后一刻安息...
suffer us not at our last hour for any plains of death...
...勿再延续
and never continuous in one stage.
在生命之中 吾遭遇死亡
In the midst of life, we are in death.
于吾欲拯救 于汝 哦 主啊
Of whom may we seek for succor but of thee, oh, Lord
吾之罪不可恕
who for our sins are justly displeased.
但是 主 上帝 最神圣的...
Yet, oh, Lord God, most holy...
...我们亲爱的姐妹的灵魂已逝
the soul of our dear sister here departed,
我们因此把她的肉体献给土地
we therefore commit her body to the ground.
土归土
Earth to earth,
尘归尘
ashes to ashes,
灰烟尽散
dust to dust
永世...
in sure and certain...
住手
Stop.
把棺材抬上来
Raise that coffin.
你做的一切是要亵渎神灵吗
Whatever do you mean by this sacrilege?
谋生 先生
Murder, sir.
我的意思是谋杀
Murder is what I mean.
对这么娇小的老妇人
Why such a deep coffin
为什么用这么深的棺材
for such a small old lady?
给你们每人一枚金币
A sovereign to each of you
如果能马上打开盖子
if you can lift the lid off that coffin in one minute.
华生
Watson.
站住 不然我就开枪了
Stop or I'll shoot.
是氯仿
It's chloroform.
她真的领教了坟墓的可怕
She's known literally the terrors of the grave.
上帝知道这对她会有什么影响
God knows what this will have done to her.
我失败了
I've failed.
我把她带回了这里
I have brought her back here
这个她童年时的乡村
to the country of her childhood
也这星球上最美丽的地方之一
which is one of the most beautiful on this planet.
她的状况有了很大改善
There has been a great improvement as a result.
那些熟悉的风景
A landscape so familiar
让她倍感亲切
and so intimate to her
我肯定有了朋友和家庭的陪伴
will prompt in time a full response I feel sure
一定会唤起她的全部反应
as will the company of friends and family
大家都非常地友善尽责
who've all been most kind and dutiful.
她可怜的哥哥 伯爵先生发狂了
Her poor brother, the Earl,
出于对那些罪犯的愤怒
is beside himself with anger at the criminals
也出于在这一切发生之前
and with mortification at his having quarreled
和Frances的那场争吵而感到悔恨
with Frances before all this happened.
最后 请接受附寄的支票
Finally, please accept the enclosed
以表我的感激之情
as a token of my gratitude
为你拯救了我亲爱的Frances
for your saving of my dear Frances,
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes,
我期待能招待你和华生医生
and I look forward to our entertainment of you and Dr. Watson
在不久的幸福未来
in a happier future.
我不能接受这个
I cannot accept it.
我拒绝因为造成了一个悲剧而被嘉奖
I refuse to be rewarded for fostering a tragedy.
我从未这样无力过
I've never suffered such a complete eclipse of my faculties.
说到无力 福尔摩斯
Well, like any eclipse, Holmes,
这只是暂时的
it's only temporary.
总有完全恢复的希望
There's every hope of a full recovery.
不见得
I wonder.
Frances?